Guide to the Reed Family Papers, 1848-1932 DAR.1937.39
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Reed Family Papers
1848-1892
ULS Archives & Special Collections
DAR.1937.39
0.42 Linear Feet (1 box)
The Reed family lived in Cross Creek Village, Washington County, Pennsylvania, from 1848 to 1892. James M. K. Reed served four terms as the Justice of the Peace in the area, starting in 1877. Letters and case files in this collection document the daily lives of family and court cases in the community. Digital reproductions of the collection are available online.
Biography
The Reed family emigrated from Ireland in the late eighteenth century and settled in western Pennsylvania. The Reeds owned a large plot of land and, as the family grew, the land was divided among the Reed family children. James M. K. Reed became a Justice of the Peace for Washington County in 1877 and served four terms. He was also a school director, auditor, supervisor, and teacher. Reed was one of the original incorporators, stockholders, and directors of the Cross Creek Cemetery Association and assisted in laying out and founding the cemetery at Cross Creek Village.
Scope and Content Notes
This collection contains two series: the first includes family papers and the second includes files and cases from James M. K. Reed's service as Justice of the Peace for Washington County. The collection material dates from 1848 to 1892. Detailed scope notes are provided at the series level.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift to Darlington Memorial Library in 1937.
Custodial History
This collection was located in the Darlington Memorial Library in the University's Cathedral of Learning until 2007 when it was moved to the ULS Archives Service Center for processing, storage, preservation and service. However, it remains in the custodianship of the ULS Special Collections Department.
Previous Citation
Reed Family Papers, 1848-1892, DAR.1937.39, Darlington Collection, Special Collections Department, University of Pittsburgh
Existence and Location of Copies
Digital reproductions of the collection are available online.
Court records -- Pennsylvania -- Washington County; Collecting of accounts -- Pennsylvania -- Washington County; Family records; Correspondence; Ledgers (Account books); Wayne County (Iowa); Summonses; Washington County (Pa.); Justices of the peace -- Pennsylvania -- Washington County; Mitchell, J. B.; Pattison, Robert E. (Robert Emory); Reed, James M. K.; Reed, Mabel; Reed family; Ferris & Steele
- Family Papers, 1848-1892; I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  Included among the family papers are two biographies of the Reed family and, most specifically, of James M.K. Reed. There is correspondences to and from various members of the Reed family, which generally discuss the health of the family and neighbors, jobs, education, and the weather. Other papers include the Excelsior Society Exhibition, purchasing orders from Ferris and Steele for basic food items, a petition to Governor Pattison against natural gas monopolies, and other papers concerning new roads in the area. Correspondence and papers from Wayne County, Iowa, regarding taxes on property owned by the Reed family are also included in this series, as are a number of receipts of transactions made by family members.
  - Biography, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1848-1859 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1860-1888 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1922-1932 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Excelsior Society, 1855 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Ferris and Steele - Purchasing Orders, 1884 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Petition to the Governor, 1884 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Roads, 1884 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Wayne Co., Iowa, 1857-1881 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Wayne Co., Iowa, 1868-1875 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Receipts, 1860-1872 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Justice of the Peace, 1864-1892; II.
  The second series contains cases James M.K. Reed presided over during his service as Justice of the Peace. Each file contains minutes from the hearing, paperwork about the dispute and details of its resolution. The cases mainly involve unpaid debts and property disagreements. There are a few files at the end of this series which contain various documents from other legal cases which are filed alphabetically.
  - Allen v. Allen, 1883 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Anderson and Johnson v. Gerrett, 1885 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Anderson v. Virtue, 1885 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Baker v. Rice, 1885 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Campbell v. Thompson, 1883 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Campbell v. Elmer and Lyle, 1882 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Fulton v. Cleland, 1879 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Hindman v. Fulton, 1879 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Hindman v. Horner, 1871 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Kemp v. Lee, 1882 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Kemp v. Potter and Dimit, 1877 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Kerr and Son v. Bailey Bros., 1883 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Kerr and Son v. Duncan, 1880 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Kerr and Son v. Noah, 1885 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Marquis Estate, 1864 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Marshall v. Fulton, 1880 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - McCorkle v. Cunningham, 1886 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - McCullough Estate, 1880 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - McFarland Estate, 1880 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - McFee v. Galbraith, 1886 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Perrine v. McClurg, 1882 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Pry v. Croner, 1881 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Reed and Anderson v. Horner, 1877 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Reed v. Jackson, 1885 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Mary Ann Reed (Pension Claim), 1883 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Scott v. Johnson, 1879 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Staiger v. Criss, 1881 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Stewart v. Cummins, 1878 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Justice of the Peace files, 1874-1879 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Justice of the Peace files, 1880-1884 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Justice of the Peace files, 1885-1892 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Justice of the Peace files, undated (Box 1, Folder 44)